Hi, welcome to everyone's favorite
segment, mailbag, where I open my mail.
Start off with a biggie. This one's
huge. It weighs about 20 kilos or
something. Unbelievable. Luckily, it's
only local cuz it cost a fortune to send
this in overseas. This only cost like 10
bucks to send locally.
It's from L Zhong, if I'm pronouncing it
correctly. Probably not. He's from
Randwick, here in
Sydney. So, let's open it. Thank you
very much, L.
So,
let's crack this puppy open.
And
what have we got?
We have
Oh,
I think we've got some old vintage PC
stuff.
We've got a 5 and 1/4 inch floppy.
There we go.
And we've got
3 and 1/2 inch floppy. We've got a power
cord.
Not approved. Hasn't got the new
insulation on the pins. Totally illegal
in this country now to import a power
cord. They're very strict on it,
apparently.
Hey, here we go. So, he still doesn't
say who he is. Just L. Thank you very
much, L. Oh, Mhm,
okay. Okay. Okay.
Let's have a look.
I won't tell you what it is.
Hang on. This is ridiculous.
It's coming. Trust me.
Wait for it.
It is a
vectorscope.
And check it out. And this will
definitely be more than a 2-minute
teardown. I'm sure. So, I'll save this
one. Thank you very much, L. If you
don't know what a vectorscope is, this
is a PAL vectorscope for video signals.
I actually used vectorscopes in my first
job back in 1980
nine, I think. 1989 working when I was
working on video stuff. Um and therefore
uh calibrating, aligning, checking,
doing everything else on PAL video
signals to get the video signal right.
And well, maybe I don't know if it
works. Maybe we can uh power it up and
uh have a look at an old-school PAL
video signal. Now, it's all bloody HD
HDMI and all that digital rubbish, but
back in the day, yep, PAL composite
signal. Surely still find a PAL
composite signal around the lab here.
Hmm.
You may not be able to see that, but
here we go. This is a Tektronix 521A
PAL vectorscope. And yes, it does NTSC
for you Yanks there, but uh this is
designed to measure video signals, all
the complex requirements of video
signals. A vectorscope is what you use.
Now, these were essential test gear for
anyone working with any sort of video
signals. My first job was working with
um
video security uh equipment, slow-scan
TV and stuff like that. And of course,
we had to actually uh check out and
diagnose video signals, and this is how
you do it. And this is actually classic.
Check out this screen here.
They've actually drawn on here in
permanent Yep, permanent marker, drawn
on here the actual waveform that they
the video waveform that they uh
required. It's like an on-screen
template to see that you know, it
matched. And that was actually quite
common. If this vectorscope was
obviously used for like one purpose. Um
and just measuring like displaying that
video signal and getting it and they had
to you know, align you know, check that
it was in It's not really a like a
template as in a like a pass/fail kind
of uh template, but it's interesting
that they've put that on there so that
they can see and instantly you plug in
your signal, does it match what we've
drawn in? So, they would have had a
reference signal, fed in their reference
signal, and then drawn over the top of
that, and then they feed in their signal
under test from the product that they're
testing, and bingo, see if it matches.
Too easy. Now, I've had to turn up the
gain on the camera here to actually uh
show you the graticule inside here, but
you can see that it's a circular
graticule like this. Now, this model um
it was obviously capable of like
displaying a video waveform, cuz if
you're familiar with a power video
waveform, that's a like a typical video
what a typical video uh signal might
look like with a stepped um you know,
like a bar type uh waveform or whatever
it is, but the what vectorscopes are
really for is they use one of these
circular type displays and it's plotting
it's basically an XY uh
plot of the chrominance uh information.
And so, the the color encoding
information on the video signal. And
from uh you know, the phases of
everything like that, you can actually
uh determine a lot about well,
everything about the video signal from
the XY uh chrominance difference
information between two different
signals.
So, you might be able to see various
little portions of the
graticule down here have these like
little like target boxes on them. And
what you do is you'd actually uh plug in
typically a
uh a bar graph
um a bar signal a bar test signal a
color bar test signal, and then your
display would actually uh
have several points in here. I'll have
to overlay a uh a typical signal on
there. I'll see if I can find one, but
it would overlay in these points and you
could see whether or not it was, you
know, out of phase and not adjusted
correctly and everything else. So, if it
was in these target areas, you knew that
your uh signal was good and everything
was aligned correctly and all your
amplifiers were properly adjusted and
things like that. And we've got
ourselves some secret squirrel
adjustments under here, like, you know,
your beam rotation, your vertical uh
clamp, and your horizontal clamp, things
like that. And then all your focus and
differential uh the whether what your
differential phase is doing and all
sorts of weird and wacky stuff. But uh
yeah, you'd have to go into the
intricacies of uh how color video
signals work to understand all of this
sort of stuff. But you can select the
lines that you wanted to use and your
calibration phase and over here you can
swap your fields and things like that.
And you you're quite sort of complicated
beast to drive. You've got to really
know what you're doing and how your
video signals work. All right, let's pop
the hood on this baby. I've never seen
inside one of these uh Tektronix
uh well, this particular model, so it'll
be interesting to see. I'm I don't even
uh know what the
vintage is. Late '70s. I have to give it
a smell test, but uh it's got these
quarter-turn screws on the top and uh
ta-da! Woohoo!
Oh, yeah, hang on.
Oh, yeah, that's got mid-'70s written
all over it.
1967.
Geez, that was before we landed on the
moon. Unbelievable. But um that's you
know, just the copyright on the PCB.
This thing could have been uh
manufactured in the '70s. These did have
a pretty big uh service life, I think.
Uh-huh. We have a found a date code on
this Motorola metal can package, 1981,
25th week. So, right there we've got a
pretty darn long lifespan. So, here we
go. I won't do a full teardown of this,
of course. It's just a
a 2-minute job, but look at all the Look
at all the looming. Look at that. It's
all tied in place. You can actually see
the
see the ties on the looms. Look at that.
And it's all stiff and wired in place.
Absolutely beautiful. And they all then
they just pop out of the wire and
harness at the correct point, go on to
their
little terminal on the board, and Bob's
your uncle. It's just
ah
beautiful. Beautiful construction. Takes
forever, of course. Like you know, it's
like there's a lot of work that goes
into producing these. It's not cheap.
It's not easy. And it's Some people say,
"Well, it's not even elegant by today's
uh you know,
sort of modern production uh standards
and things like that." And it's not. It
takes a lot of effort. You wouldn't do
something like this today with all these
cable looms and things like that. It's
just, you know, really old-school stuff.
And for those playing along at home,
here's the back of the thing. We've got
our CRT uh cover on here. And our
old-school uh transistor covers, our TO3
packages. Well, that's a TO3 package.
That's a small one under there. And uh
using the chassis as a heatsink.
Beautiful. We've got all our inputs and
uh outputs on the back here. And um
astigmatism, geometry, all that
fantastic stuff you needed for CRTs back
in the days. Of course, you wouldn't use
CRTs these days if you had a modern
vectorscope.
Does anyone actually make a modern
vectorscope? Maybe they do. All right,
this is scary. I'm going to power it up.
We have a green light.
Green light's good.
Come on.
You can do it.
Scale lumina ah scale illumination. No.
Intensity. No.
No.
Ah. Wah wah wah wah.
Well, our intensity's all the way up.
Our scale illumination I mean our scale
illumination should just be like a light
bulb on the outside that just, you know,
lights up the lights up the scale. So,
it can't even do that. So, yeah.
So, thank you very much L Chung if I'm
pronouncing that correctly. He doesn't
have a first name. He's just L. It That
could be his real first name. Could be
one letter. Who knows? Anyway, thank you
very much for sending in this
interesting beast. Maybe we can do a um
more interesting teardown. I'll try and
figure out why the damn thing is uh
is not doing anything. Hmm. Anyway,
awesome. And no, I haven't changed. But,
we have someone guest
mailbag opener. Take it away.
Hello there. I'm Ryan Tillett sin. You
probably have no idea who I am.
Well, yeah, pretty much. But, I am in
here for work experience. No, I will not
tell you the name of the school,
otherwise they may get angry at me. But,
yeah, I'll be helping out David with his
mail bagging today. And we got this
package here. So, let's give it an open.
And you know nothing about engineering.
You're here for video blogging.
Yes, I am. I want to be a YouTuber
myself and I think and apparently when
David Jones said, "Yeah, he can come
along. He can learn a bit." Boy, was I
excited. So, yeah.
All right. Well, let's open a mailbag
item.
Let's do it.
Go. Go for it.
You can use a knife if you like.
Love it.
Imagine the
OH&S problems here, folks. I don't want
to know. Let's just hope the school
doesn't see this.
Let's see.
Oh, what's this?
Hmm.
Whoa.
David, you tell me, what is this thing?
Show us.
It's a Fluke One Touch Network
Assistant. Ah, one of those for those
network geeks. For testing networks.
So, you plug your RJ you plug your
ethernet in the top and it um yeah.
Mhm. Very useful.
Ah, yeah, I think it's from Samuel
Pitches.
Thank you very much, Samuel. Is there
any backstory to it?
Ah, let's see. To
one for tear down Tuesday.
Nothing wrong with mania as far as I can
see. Just the battery pack is a bit worn
out and the charging port seems to be a
bit flaky.
We can work around that.
Love the show and watch every episode
and so he's into all those fixing
things.
If you're ever down in the world's most
livable city, please let me know as it'd
be great to say hi in person. Of course.
All the best, Samuel.
Oh, he's not from bloody Melbourne, is
he? Yeah, he's got to rub it in. World's
most Yeah, he's rubbing it in.
Unbelievable. This Australia was the
world's most livable city at one point
and now it's bloody Melbourne.
Mhm.
Yeah, we hate the Melbourners.
Yes.
Yeah, Sydney all the way. We've got two
landmarks.
So, Samuel has sent in this Fluke One
Touch 10/100 Network Assistant.
Obviously got some whiz-bang graphical
LCD on it. Whether or not it's color, I
don't know. And tada, check it out.
Requires tongue at the right angle.
Center negative. Center negative.
Center negative pin. Oh, that's just
evil. Isn't that right?
Mhm.
Evil. Yep, Ryan agrees even though he's
no idea what I'm talking about. Still,
it's evil. Trust me. Yes. And it comes
from Vact, whoever the hell they are and
their asset register. And um yeah, it's
just one of these uh
network uh things. You plug it in and
you can diagnose your network and all
that sort of stuff. Is that just some
sort of RS232 diagnostic port? I don't
know about my network engineer and I'm
sure those out there in the know will uh
be screaming at me and uh
there you go. Plus minus and 9 volts
ish.
All right, I've got 9 volts going in
this puppet. It's showing like 1
milliamp on standby.
It's probably not surrounded. Oh, excuse
you.
And
power button down defaults restored.
Yeah, okay, thank you very much. It does
actually
work. Oh, little animation. Oh, what
happened there? And there we go. We're
into the main menus and all that sort of
stuff and uh
network health
all that sort of jazz. Oh, there you go.
I can actually
I can plug that into my network here if
I wanted to. Uh except when the bloody
probes fall off. Yeah. And quick
2-minute teardown. We're in like Flynn.
Check out the nickel screening
on that. That'll be conductive, of
course.
Check that out. There we go. Yep. And
we've got double-sided load on there and
components both sides looks
very
professional and high quality
as you'd expect from uh well, it's Fluke
Networks, which is not Fluke
Instruments. So, totally different
company. No surprises for finding um a
separate
um isolation board for your ethernet
here with all your isolators and uh
stuff like that. They sound relays. I
think we heard some relays click before.
So, it's going to have all sorts of, you
know, overload and safety and meet all
sorts of uh
whiz-bang standards, whatever the
standards are for
network connections and things like
that. And well, yeah, so that's going to
be pretty ordinary. What processor does
it use down in there? Let's take a quick
squeeze. There we go. Nice little
board-to-board inner connect there.
There's the main board. It's got network
specific chip sets and things like that.
I won't even bother looking those up.
Those playing along at home can do that.
Lots of discrete transistors down here.
Are they
diodes
for some sort of protection maybe? I
don't know, but that's separate and this
board here
just sits in there. There we go. We've
got a nice uh
0.1 inch header which goes down to our
display board and we're in like Flynn.
Analog Devices
DSP
Here it is. There we go.
That's the ADSP 2181.
So, they've got some DSPs. We've got a
Xilinx um
uh CPLD
in there. We've got two of those. Are
they the same? 3164s, yep. We've got
ourselves a big unpopulated uh connect
to here. That's absolutely massive. That
might have been a development connector
or maybe it's
for a different model perhaps. I don't
know, but it's on the top side here. So,
it would have
maybe it's, you know, a different
interface to
instead of that one. I don't know. My
best guess there would be that's some
sort of development uh test connector,
something like that. Does anyone else
think this board might have been auto
routed?
Perhaps. It just looks kind of auto
routerish
to me. Aha, we actually have
a PC compatible processor. This is the
AMD AM
um
188. This is an 80C188
compatible processor, i.e. 8088 IBM PC
compatible. Or Intel, you know, everyone
associates it with the IBM of course,
but um yeah, it's a There you go. So,
that's running all the main code and
interface and everything else on the LCD
and all that sort of stuff. So, software
development would be pretty easy. But,
obviously, they're doing all the
real-time networking stuff. Obviously,
not fast enough to do it in the main
CPU here. So, they've got to do it
inside the DSP. And well, there's not
much more to say about that. I see a
JTAG programming header there. And uh
that's about it. I don't think the 80188
has a JTAG interface, so that'll be for
the analog
devices one. So, yeah, maybe that's what
they've got the
this in-system development connector
for. Perhaps it's for the 80188.
Perhaps. I don't know. Anyway, just a
couple of FPGAs and a 80188 processor
and a DSP doing all the heavy list-
lifting on that puppy. And of course,
we've got some power supply stuff around
here, and Bob's your uncle. Excellent.
Thank you very much, Samuel, for
sending that one in. Interesting. I
might actually have to try and hook that
up to my network and see what it says.
And here I was trying to figure out why
this case wouldn't go back together.
Yeah, can you figure it out?
Oh.
Actually, I rather like this design.
It's incredibly
simplistic. How it goes together and the
screws from the outside screw into here
and hold the boards in. So, there's only
these two internal screws, and that's
and that's it, apart from the LCD
display board. I just like the
simplicity of that. It's very well
designed.
And so, next up, we have one from
California, US, from someone named
Donald B. Butkin. So, let's take a look.
I'm maybe going a bit little box here.
All right.
Don't worry, I know how to use knives. I
swear.
There we go.
All right.
Um let's see. Oh.
It's a dinosaur.
Oh, look at that. It's a little robotic
dinosaur.
Naked.
Yeah.
Oh, well, apparently this one lost all
its fur. Oh, it's still got some with
some sponge.
Okay, that's cute. Oh, wow. Thanks,
Donald. You certainly know
You certainly know what David likes.
Possibly what Sega likes.
Yeah, I can just see this in a Sega
game.
Yeah, it's
I think that's rubber that the head's
made out of.
Mhm.
And oh.
Yeah, I think it's eyes still move.
Animatronic eyes.
Mhm.
Doesn't say apparently it doesn't work
anymore though, but hey, it's the
presentation that makes the it all good.
So, thank you very much, Donald. Um this
is
fascinating. Roar. It's an animatronic
dinosaur and um he was built by a
startup company called Ugears.
Um that was right across from the street
from Research Advantage, which is
where
Donald works. And apparently we can get
this puppy going.
Yeah. Wow, it's got a It's got a USB
port.
And his mouth opens.
Uh yeah, you just need to kind of force
it open.
Cool.
Very timely with the new Jurassic Park,
which I haven't seen yet. Have you seen
the new Jurassic Park?
No. I'm not much of a movie person.
No? Yeah. Okay.
It's pretty cool.
All right. Cuz I think the first
Jurassic Park would have come out before
you were born. Maybe maybe not.
No.
When was the first Jurassic Park?
I don't know. I'd have to look it up.
I don't know. But yeah, that's very
cool. That looks like a very complicated
beast.
Wow. There's a lot of stuff that goes
into that. That's fantastic. And
apparently,
um we might be able to get it going. Uh
7.2 volts that would imply it's got a
rechargeable uh packing there of some
description.
Awesome. Too bad all its skin's gone,
but it's nice that we can actually see
it and it's torn down. Very cool. It's
got uh there's an SD card slot on the
bottom. Don talks about an OS
or something, USB port, and little
sensor pads for the feet. So, it knows
when it
goes
down like that and it can twist its body
and its tail and
all sorts of jazz. And you notice a
speaker on there. So, it's probably
It's definitely got to have sound like
And animatronic eyes.
That's terrific, but they folded. Um it
was done in 2007
uh by a startup company and they folded
in 2009 apparently. So, yeah, I guess
nobody bought um
an animatronic dino. Aw, sad face.
So, here it is. Isn't it cute? Aw, Don,
this is like one of the best mailbag
items ever. It's so cute. I want like a
proper one with the skin and everything.
It turns out this is the Pleo. That's
his name, Pleo. And this is an
animatronic dinosaur. As he said,
developed by a company called Ugobe uh
back in 2006
and it was released in 2007
and for about 350 US bucks and sold a
whole bunch of them. Like they sold out
within days or something, like a couple
of days. The first couple of thousand
sold out and they ultimately sold
100,000 of these things. I
I can't say that I've ever heard of it.
Maybe I
did see it back at the day and you know,
I went, "Oh, okay. It's an animatronic
dinosaur." But now I've got kids, I
understand, you know, that something
like this is fantastic. And you'll
notice that there we go. There's his
camera in there. He's got all these
sensors. They look like infrared
transmitter and receiver in there and
he's got operating eyes and mouth and he
can actually sense things that you put
in his mouth. And the whole idea behind
Pleo, oh, his battery his guts fell out.
Um
The whole idea behind Pleo is that like
he goes through these different stages
of development. Like he, you know, like
he's just like when you first get him,
he's programmed to be like a newborn and
then he goes through like a a 5-hour
process of being like a newborn dinosaur
where you, you know, teach him to open
his eyes, you stroke him and, you know,
he's got all these sensors on him that
allow you to interact with him. And as I
said, sensors on the feet and he can
recognize when you touch his feet and
things like that. So he'll lift up his
Um you know, his paw. That's not the
correct his foot.
Dinosaurs don't have paws.
Anyway, um here's some like footage.
I'll put in some footage of him actually
operating Pleo and he's just so cute.
And this is nude Pleo. This is without
all his skin. Anyway, apparently the
company went bust or whatever.
Uh
uh around about like after they shipped
them and then another company uh came in
and now it's the Pleo rb. And
apparently, I think you can still get
him or the website's still there and you
can get all sorts of accessories and all
sorts of things. Anyway, yeah, he's
designed to go through like a learning
stage and then he learns to walk and all
sorts of things. So, really
it's just fantastic and so cute. I'm
going to have to get myself one with
like the proper one with the skin on and
everything. Seeing it just
I'd go ape over this.
So, I picked a Camarasaurus because the
Camarasaurus was the most abundant of
the of the sauropods in North America
and you can actually find full fossil
evidence of these. That's a juvenile and
and so we actually went in there's a
book called Walking on Eggshells where
they found actual uh sauropod skin in
Patagonia. And the picture from the book
so when I I I told the sculptor use use
this bump pattern whatever you can to to
copy that. So, uh there's the motor and
so and about this time, you know, all
these other people are starting to help.
Here's an example what we did with the
skull. There's the skull. Um there's my
drawing of a skull. There's kind of the
skin version of the soft tissue. There's
the mechanism that would go in there
kind of a Geneva drive. There's some
SolidWorks versions of it. Here's some
SLA parts of the same thing and then uh
these are really crude pieces we're just
doing some tests here. And there's uh
kind of the first uh exploded view or or
see-through view. There's the uh first
SLA version and it already kind of has
the feel. It has kind of a cuteness
already. And the thing about blending
science and art and this
multidisciplinary stuff is you can do a
robot then you go go to go back and do
the the shape and then you go back and
forth. The servos in the front legs we
had to shape those like muscles. They
had to fit within the envelope. There
was there was a a
tremendous amount of of work to get all
that working right. All the neck and the
tail are cable so it moves smoothly and
organically. And then of course you're
not done yet. You have to get the uh
look for the skin. The skin's a whole
'nother thing probably the hardest part.
So, you hire artists and and you try to
get the look and feel of the character.
Now this now we're character designers,
right? And then, 4 years and uh 10
million dollars later, we have uh her
little Pleo. The The These are These are
These are little Pleos, and you you can
probably see see them. The This I on
purpose um they they go through life
stages. So, when you first get them,
they're they're babies, and then the
more you have them, kind of the older
they get, and they kind of learn through
their behavior. So, this guy's listening
to my voice here, but they have uh 40
sensors uh all over their body. They
have uh seven processors. They have um
14 motors. They have uh
And but you don't care, do you? They're
just cute, right? That's the idea.
That's the idea. We're Okay, he's
hungry. I'll show you what he's been
doing for
for 4 years. Here. Here. Here. Have some
money, Pleo.
There you go. See?
That's what That's what the investors
think, that it's just
So, they they they They're really sweet
little guys, and um we're hoping that um
you know, our belief is that that humans
need to feel empathy towards
towards things in order to be more
human, and we think we can uh
help that out by having
little creatures that you can love. Now,
these are not robots. They're kind of
lovebots, you know? They They do change
over time, but mostly they evoke um
a feeling of caring.
Okay, Pleo.
Here we go. Oh.
That was on.
Oh, it helps if I turn my damn power
supply on. Here we go.
Ooh, I heard something.
A little peep from the speaker.
Come on, Pleo. Come on.
What?
It's alive.
Is it?
Come on.
You there?
He's drawing 1.2 watts.
Uh
Hello. Huh?
Come on, Pleo.
Come on.
Come on, Pleo. Come on.
He's so sleepy.
And he's obviously look these um sensor
pads on the top these are capacitive
these look like capacitive pads so like
when you pat him then he obviously
recognizes
Yeah.
These you know when you touch his cuz
there's shielding once again around the
legs here.
And
Yeah.
He's doing something although Donald
said he might need an an operating
system upgrade.
Oh, come on.
Poor thing.
Come on Pleo.
His legs are up. His eyes are open.
I'm Pleo.
Oh.
Aw.
Aw, it's okay. It's okay.
I think he's scared.
Yeah.
That is cool.
Aw, he's tired.
Aw.
He's gone to sleep again.
Well, we know it's alive. It's alive.
It's adorably alive.
Aw.
Poor thing.
So that's the key you got to pick him up
and he wakes up
and uh then he obviously goes into like
a sleep routine. Oh, he's going to pull
his own
power cord out. See? He goes to sleep
and then you
pick him up and he'll uh
Oh.
He wakes up.
Go Pleo.
Aw.
He's so sleepy.
So yeah, obviously that's a uh
capacitive sensor
touch pad so when you go pat him
um it can detect that you're trying to
pat him there's you know, most probably
a uh
a uh a accelerometer in there, of
course, you know, a tilt when he's uh
tipped over and things like that. And as
I said, little sensor pads on his feet,
they might help him walk or maybe I've
seen like videos of people like touch
his foot, just like lightly touch it.
So, there's maybe there's another
capacitive sensor in there. Although,
this one around here has to be there's
no other reason. There's no shielding
reason for that really. So, it's got to
be a capacitive uh touch sensor again.
And uh
yeah, and it's got a USB camera. So,
like I've actually seen a video where he
actually walks towards the edge like
this and knows that he's going to go
over the edge and he sort of goes
and sort of backs off a bit from the
edge. So, there's a lot of um
uh sensor and firmware intelligence
which goes into this. And all the
articulating
mechanisms, that's quite nice. There's
his rubber
rubber skin. This one's just been hacked
off
completely. Whether or not this is a
prototype or whether or not this is a
production unit, I don't think uh
Donald's um Donald says in his letter,
no, I'm not sure. But, uh
yeah, I mean, it looks fairly production
what you'd get inside a production unit,
I suspect. So,
there you go. So cute. Pleio.
Say bye-bye.
And I think he's got some uh maybe
infrared sensors in his
mouth there cuz he apparently comes with
some sort of leaf or something you can
train him to eat and uh
all sorts of stuff. Brilliant. So, thank
you very much, Donald. That is quite
possibly the coolest thing I've ever had
on mailbag. And I so want to tear him
down, but it's it's
it doesn't look particularly easy. Um
Um,
it's always easy to tear down. It's
never easy to put them back together in
uh working
condition. I rather uh this battery uh
packs
interesting. I originally thought double
A's go in there, but
I don't think so based on that uh
uh configuration there. And then the
springs at the bottom, and that just
goes in there like that, and then that
clips in there. That's rather uh
quite neat. But uh yeah, apparently you
can still buy the uh battery packs for
them. I'm not sure what like the new one
is supposed to have all new experiences,
and you know, the Pleo rb is supposed to
have all new
you know, mostly probably just firmware
upgrades uh really as opposed to uh it's
probably still the original
hardware platform, I suspect. But
anyway, if uh
anyone knows any more details, then uh
that is fascinating. I would I want to
do more videos on Pleo. That's just
awesome. Thanks, Donald. Sagan's going
to love it. All right, Ryan, let's check
this one out. This one's anonymous.
Where does it come from?
Oh, bloody Melbourne again.
Mhm.
Bloody Melbourne. We hate Melbourne,
don't we? Yeah.
Yeah. Melbournes have all the fun.
All right.
They get all the uh
they get all the events.
Yeah, all the excitement on YouTube.
Actually, Melbourne have a really big
YouTube community. Do you know that?
They got We ain't got nothing here in
Sydney, but Melbournes get together all
the time.
All these Melbourne YouTubers, and uh
yeah, they have tons of events.
Um
In my opinion, Australia needs more
YouTubers in general.
We just died.
Ooh, what have we got?
Ooh.
I was going through a box of assorted
manuals I scored a long time ago, and we
have
a whole bunch
of manuals. Thank you very much, John.
John sent them.
And uh he found quite a few duplicates.
What's that one?
Uh, the 6034A
users guide.
So, HP?
HP.
Before HP became Agilent and then they
became Keysight. And we hate Keysight,
don't we, Ryan?
Mhm.
Yeah, that's just not the name. It's
hopeless. And we have a system to a
6034 system DC power supply complete
with
pornographic foldout schematics.
Wow, look at that.
Oh.
Wow, isn't that beautiful?
So, John has kindly sent in all these
old HP
um
manuals and stuff. Terrific. Neat. The
6034A.
Yeah, it's your new friend, the 6034A.
Then we've got the matching service
manual for this, the operating and
service manual. And as I said, just
yeah, pornographic
foldouts of uh all the circuits.
Fantastic stuff. Love it. And all the
board overlays and uh the bill of
materials and everything else. Terrific.
Fantastic. They spared no expense.
People don't do manuals like these
anymore. Oh, the 1700 series um analog
scope with the multimeter attachment on
top. Oh, that was the duck's guts back
in the day. I'll tell you what.
I'll tell you that for nothing. And
there's our There's our power supply.
You can tell that's a power supply just
based on the topology. There's our
series pass uh transistor up there and
uh that's the and you've got the
regulator servo happening there. You've
got some feedback stuff happening and
Bob's your uncle. Of course, before the
internet, right?
Mhm.
Yes. Yes. I've been telling him all
about it. I've been showing him my data
books here before the internet and PDFs
came along, right?
I'm a whippersnapper.
Young whippersnapper. So, we've got our
application notes. This is where you
found all your information. You've got
to eliminate time base errors from your
oscilloscope measurements cuz back in
the day it was, you know, none of this
crystal oscillator timebase rubbish. No,
they'd have a, you know, an RC
oscillator, probably,
in the in the old HP scopes. And we've
got our service manual for the 1727. Oh,
look at the
Look at that. Look at that.
Wow, unbelievable.
It's all happening. And wow,
like they'd actually be hard to scan in
cuz they're so big and long and
complicated. And that's yeah, that's
looks like part of a system wiring
diagram there.
And whoosh, wow, it's just chock full.
Look at that. That's just all service
information line. Look at the bill at
Look at the beautiful diagrams, exploded
assembly diagram views which they did
back in the day. Someone actually drew
that, you know. You have a draft, sorry,
you have a draftsman
back then. It's not a draft person, you
had a draftsman back then. It might have
been a woman, but they were called
draftsman and they didn't complain about
it. And
there's all the front panel controls.
And
beautiful. And the universal counter,
once again, operating and service
manuals. These are worth their weight in
gold, they really are. If you're looking
to buy second-hand gear on eBay,
and uh just check to see if the uh
service manual's available. Fantastic.
Oh, look, we got some diff pairs
happening in there and
all sorts of
Whoop.
How do I
put that back together? It's like
folding one of those maps. Have you ever
folded tried to fold a topographic map?
There's a certain
way you've got to do it, certain art to
folding those.
Brilliant. Awesome. Thanks, John. And
we've got the operating manual as well.
Fantastic. Terrific stuff. Next up, we
have one from Jacob with a K.
Um Jacob's uh Steno. He's from the old
dart, the UK.
And uh
And
let's check out what
he sent.
Oh.
It's a bit weird here with a second a
second person
with a knife. I don't know where to
I'm pointing the knife. I don't want to
uh
I can imagine the paperwork if I stabbed
you.
Oh, that's a lot of paperwork.
paperwork. Oh,
it's just not No, there's something uh
Sorry, I'm going to have to go to this.
It's just We've got duct tape. So,
we're going
My advice to anyone who's doing
packaging, please don't use too much
duct tape. It's It's I know you're
trying to be safe and secure, but
it's just not easy to open.
It's over the top, isn't it? It's a bit
much. It's a bit much.
Yeah.
Just so you know.
Mhm.
Handy tip there. Thanks, Ron.
All right.
Bubble wrap.
You like popping bubble wrap?
Oh, yeah.
Ooh. Um yep, Jacob. He's a first-year
electronics engineering student at
Slovakia.
Wow, he's studying in the UK, though.
There you go. It's an international
world.
Sweet.
And he's an electronics hobbyist. Let's
see what Jacob sent in.
More bubble wrap.
More of this. There we go, pop that.
Yeah.
Joys of uh
Therapeutic, isn't it?
Uh yeah.
Love it.
Let's go. What have we got?
It relieves so much stress by doing this
all day.
Can.
Is school stressful these days? Is high
school stressful?
A little bit.
Yeah.
It probably gets even more stressful
when you get to year 11, since I'm in
year 10 right now, but
he gets through it. Yep, you survive.
It's all a matter of survival, high
school, isn't it? It's pretty
much yeah, until you have you have to
your friends or something. From school
works, and other from bullies.
Yeah.
And all that stuff.
Yep.
Woah, it's a
cable simulator. Woohoo, check it out.
Oop.
There we go.
And it's for um
simulator, I guess, based on the symbols
are twisted pair cable, 300 kHz. Ah,
yeah, ISDN bandwidth and all that sort
of jazz. So, yeah, really old school. Um
Everything's fiber these days. They're
not running Jeez, even I've got fiber in
the lab here. Well, not fiber to the
lab. I still got twisted pair coming
from the MDF room down the bottom up to
here. So, you know, we still use copper.
Ryan just called me a grandpa?
Yeah. The way you were looking at those
magazines, you're pretty much a grandpa.
Yeah, young whipper bloody
whippersnappers. I don't know. Anyway,
Jacob with a K has sent in this cable
simulator. I haven't seen it before.
It's a 5260, a division of
It comes from
Ah, jeez, your logo's all tucked away up
in there. How do you expect people to
know your product if it's tucked away?
Processing
telecom technologies, a division of
Adtran or something like that. Anyway,
Adtran, I think.
Adtran, okay. There we go. So, what we
can do is just switching the distant
different distances here, and I believe
these are
feet. So, you can you know, whack in 500
ft and stuff like that, and you've got
access to the rear panels. At the
bottom, it's showing that up to 10,000
ft here, 300 kHz
bandwidth and 100 kHz bandwidth if you
want to go Well, if you want to include
like all of them, so you can if you put
them all on, that's your maximum length,
I believe. I love how these switch in
the little eye like that. It's just like
they really stand out. Really good.
Nobody does those anymore. I love those.
They those indicators, they're just
terrific.
Makes it feel like it's more alive that
way.
Yeah, kind of, you know, like sort of,
you know, the dinosaur pleo, right? You
know, he's got little eyes and he opens
up and wake up. Wake up. We need power.
It's like hell.
I'm sorry, Dave. I can't do that. All
right, 2-minute tear down.
And uh
That's all. Holy goodness.
Look at that.
That's a lot of yellow.
Rocky. USA. USA. USA. Land of the
tinellum capacitor.
Except no, because Australia has the
largest tinellum mines in the world, I
believe. Hmm. Sorry, Yanks. Now, you may
be wondering what's going on in here,
and I think I have an idea cuz I've done
cable simulation in the past. As you
know, I worked on big uh, you know,
10-km
long uh seismic arrays and things like
that. And what they what I believe
they're doing here is this is like as it
says, it's a cable simulator. So, what
they've got is they will actually join
these all these lump all these elements.
So, it break up the you simulate the
cable into all these discrete elements
in series like this. So, you know, RLC
because every cable has DC resistance,
of course, so you got to have some
resistance in there. Each cable has some
inductance, so you got to have some
got to have some inductance in there,
and each cable has capacitance, of
course, so you got to include that. And
the way you simulate it in length is to
break it down into little elements and
join them all in series like that. And
you snake it around, and you can
simulate your long cable line. So, let's
see if we can see that
happening here. You can see that this is
sort of going in
here, and then going to the next array,
which then goes to the next one, and
then goes to the next, and there we go,
in series, and then goes to the next
one, boom, boom, boom, like that, and
all the way along.
Now, this is fascinating. I was wrong
about these being tantalums. I just like
I opened the thing, and they were
tantalum-looking
devices, but of course Dale do not make
tantalum capacitors. And I thought they
were a little bit sort of too short and
stubby and high to sort of be tantalums,
but you know, yeah, they were like they
looked like tantalums for all the world,
but they're not. Look, 10R8. You might
think that's a resistor, but I suspect
that is not. I suspect that puppy's an
inductor.
And what these little mouth packages
here you thought might have been
inductors, well, they are. I mean,
there's a couple of little tiny, but you
can see them. You can see the turns
on there. So, are they like a spiral-cut
mouth resistors  tiny inductors?
I think I believe these are inductors,
and uh
these puppies are a little uh
little resistors, like very low-value
resistors. And of course, we have our uh
multi-layer uh ceramic caps here, but
yeah, that's just sort of back to front
to what you initially would have thought
when you first glance at this thing.
It's interesting to note that we've got
different configurations for these
lumped elements here, too. This one, for
example, has these two
um
uh 10.8 uh microhenry inductors here in
parallel, and then in parallel with
these two other spiral-cut resistors.
You can see the traces all paralleled
up. But this one here, this will just be
a single. Look, that's just the inductor
on its own, and then we've got the two
uh resistors in parallel and another
another inductor on its own. So, yeah,
it's certainly
all over the shop, different
configurations. They're
tweaking it to get exactly the
simulation that they want. And then
under these two
top boards, we've got another one in the
opposite direction, which is very
similar, but uh slightly different.
We've got the once again diode uh
inductors
there, but uh they're black instead of
uh
a very confusing tantalum-like yellow.
And
then under there,
we've got more. More arrays. Look at
them.
Wow.
As far as the eye can see.
Unbelievable.
So, there's one,
two,
three,
and then there's a fourth, which is
another one of these puppies down on the
bottom layer. Unbelievable.
And it turns out this puppy can uh
simulate up to 60,000 ft for you Yanks.
Um up to 100 kHz bandwidth or uh 20,000
uh ft up to 300 kHz bandwidth. And of
course, you just switch them in. It's a
complete passive um
RLC
network array. And that's all it is. You
can switch the thing in, and uh there
you go.
Simple cable simulator. But that's yeah,
I've um done these sorts of things
before, and you just break them down
into individual individual RLC
elements so that you can simulate a
cable as a lumped element array of RLC
all the way down the cable. And here's
the basic Dave CAD model of what I'm
talking about. These lumped elements
here, you can actually simulate any
length uh cable. This is a very just a
simplistic way to do it. Just a simple
RLC, and you can get in there and like
put them in the bottom and add you know
capacitors aren't ideal and inductors
aren't ideal blah blah blah. But you
know, basically you can simulate a long
cable line just with a lumped element
array like that. So thank you very much
Jacob for sending that in. We haven't
seen one of these before on the blog and
they are fascinating and essential tools
for simulating lines and people will
actually take this as a portal one. You
take it out in the field of course and
it's completely passive um and you can
hook the thing um
There you go. You can hook hook the
thing up and you can do cable
simulations out in the field when you're
doing installs and then nothing takes
its place. I mean you can't carry around
a 60,000 ft reel of reel of cable to do
your simulation on. So these are
actually a quite a decent way to do it.
So thank you very much Jacob,
fascinating. Next up we've got one from
China but it's not your typical typical
Chinese product. It's from uh Peter who
clued me up on this. Thank you very much
Peter. Um look straps and all sorts of
things on this. Uh
from Siemens and uh
of course
Siemens uh do have
tons of industrial stuff.
So I want
This will make an interesting tear down
I suspect.
So
probably even more than a 2-minute tear
down. And uh
Yeah, use that man strength.
Yeah, we
need man strength.
All right and
these are
if you're into your industrial
motor controllers, inverters, things
like that. It's a Siemens
inverter. So these are fascinating
devices like real high-powered stuff.
You know, driving big motors and things
like that need lots of high currents and
these are apparently
Peter assures me, real
nice
that
Woah.
That's a Yeah, it's a nice It's a
Sinamats Sinamics Sinamics V20
um industrial
motor inverter controller thing. So,
these will make fascinating teardowns.
There's lots of technology that goes
into these puppies.
You know something that with all these
danger signs, it's got to be good.
It's got to be nasty. Yeah, it's going
to get hot and uh it's all high voltage,
blah blah blah, exclamation mark. Yep,
what's that?
It's got a little plug on the front. I
don't know what plugs in there.
It seems to be a safety thing cuz you
know, you know how metal can get in
there. It's like that's to protect it.
Oh, yeah, the little plug. Yeah, if
you're got an industrial environment,
you want to keep that
Yeah.
little plug on there until you It's
probably like a little programming port
or something, maybe. So, yeah.
Fantastic. Thanks, Peter. These are
going to make for a great teardown. And
we've got a second one here. And you
were telling me about Nintendo 64s.
About my Nintendo 64 teardown. Tell us
about the story there. What's the
history?
Yeah, it's a apparently, um when it came
to the Nintendo 64, I did actually
didn't know this myself until I was
AVGN. When uh there was this company
called
uh Wisdom Tree who was making these
Bible Adventure games for the original
Nintendo systems. So, when Nintendo
realized this when they made the
Nintendo 64,
they made a lockout chip in the Nintendo
64 to stop it from happening again. And
the only games that would be that would
allow the Nintendo 64 uh games licensed
by Nintendo.
However, Wisdom Tree did find a way to
override it. When it was a game called
Super Noah's Ark 3D
where um
they made a deal with Id who had
apparent who were apparently Ed was
annoyed with Nintendo cuz Nintendo had
toned down the violence in Wolfenstein
3D. So, to get back at them,
they canceled the design for and
software and stuff for Wolfenstein 3D
over to Wisdom Tree, and they made the
mockery known as
Super Noah's Ark.
And in order to override the system,
they actually made the cartridge so that
you plugged it in first, and there was
like this slot on top where another
could be put inserted. You would insert
a Nintendo
licensed Nintendo game on top, and that
would override the lockout chip.
Got it. There you go.
They were some clever cards.
Yeah. I didn't know ID did stuff that
was on the Nintendo. I thought they were
PC games only.
Yeah, I think it was I think they were
they were it was for some other system,
but I think Nintendo I'm not sure how
Nintendo got involved in some way. I
would have to do more research on it.
Fascinating. Is that what you want to
get into? Maybe gaming videos or
something?
I do.
Retro games?
Um well, not retro.
Well, retro to you, not retro to me.
Retro to me is '80s. Retro to you is
what? 2000s?
Yeah, somewhere like 10 years ago. 1990s
to 2000s.
Yep. Cool. Another gaming channel coming
up. Check out Ryan's Oh, he doesn't have
a channel yet, do you?
I'm hoping to make one.
Hoping to make one. We'll link it in
when he does. Awesome. And we've got
ourselves another controller. Oh, that
looks jazzier. Look at that.
Here we go. That's spunky. Nice big
heatsink on the back.
Awesome. Thanks, Peter.
So, thank you very much, Peter, for
sending these puppies in. We're going to
do a definitely do a separate teardown
of these. Now, Peter made the point of
explaining that they actually
these contain really advanced IGBT
modules like completely snotted in
silicon, and you know, really fan
fabulous stuff like that, but more
amazing than that, they actually um
model the behavior of the thermals of
the IGBT transistors and stuff like
that. They model those and they're and
there's actually BGAs and things in here
to actually do some advanced thermal and
other modeling of the stuff that happens
within these things and that's how they
get the efficiency
in such a small package. It I think
there's a lot more to these than what
they look. Just not a bunch of just
off-the-shelf components from Digikey
whacked in a nice case and whacked the
Siemens label on it. There's a lot of
advanced tech which goes into these
high-power
motor drive inverters. And they also
model all the magnetics of the motors as
well. So, there's lots of BGAs in here,
lots of processing grunt in here which
simulates the thermal behavior of not
only the power semiconductor devices,
but the motors that they're driving, all
the magnetics and everything else you
can imagine. What sort of you know,
horsepower is required to do that sort
of modeling? So, it's all done inside
here. That's how they get these the
efficiencies inside these things and
they can have, I guess, relatively small
heat sinks. I'm not sure about the
the actual performance of these things.
A 0.33 horsepower motor for this puppy
here. Anyway, um yeah, apparently really
advanced tech in here. So, it could be
fascinating to take it apart and if I
can get any more technical info on how
they do that modeling and stuff like
that, we'll definitely include that in a
follow-up teardown. Thank you very much,
Peter. So, thank you very much everyone
who sent in stuff to mailbag and thank
you very much for Ryan for helping out.
He's here all week, folks. He's here all
week. Awesome. And hopefully, you'll
maybe be assembling some of the
pick-and-place machines. Maybe. Perhaps.
Sounds like fun.
We'll see. Awesome. Catch you next time.
Roar.
You are a dork.
Duh.
It's tough being a work experience kid,
but in the end, it makes you productive.